[trafic]
[cell phone alarm rings]
[Guédira sighs]
[musique inquiétante]
[woman speaking indistinctly over PA]
[train horn blares]
Monsieur, votre billet. Merci.
Monsieur, votre billet.
Messieurs-dames, contrôle des billets.
[musique dramatique]
[indistinct chatter]
[Claire] Raoul !
[seagulls crying]
Raoul !
[garçon] Arrête !
[garçon] Lâche-moi !
[tires screech]
[musique angoissante]
[Claire] Raoul ?
[Assane] Raoul ?
[Guédira] Lupin ?
You're looking for a kid
dressed as Arsène Lupin?
[Claire] Oui ! Un petit garçon !
He's 14. He's our son.
He's got a top hat and… he has brown skin.
-Brown skin?
-[Claire] Yeah.
I saw a kid
fighting with a guy in the parking lot.
Attendez !
Raoul !
They went that way.
In a gray BMW.
-Tell me what the guy looked like.
-Black. Beige coat.
Bad beard, thin.
Assane, Jesus!
C'est de ta faute !
The guy from the train!
Who the fuck was that?
You lied to me!
Assane, no! What are you doing?
Tu fais quoi ?
Let go of that car!
Let go or I'll call the cops.
No. No police. All right?
Just calm down. I'll handle it. Okay?
- Je vais les appeler.
- Fais-moi confiance !
Je vais ramener Raoul.
Fais-moi confiance.
J'ai plus confiance depuis longtemps.
Claire, pas la police.
[Claire panting]
What are you doing here?
I wanna help. I'm coming.
[engine starts]
[Claire panting]
[vrombissement]
[suspenseful music playing]
Claire, your rehearsal go good?
Tu veux pas que je marche avec toi ?
What did I do?
What's going on?
Claire?
[Claire sighs]
Not everything is about you, Assane.
[soft music playing]
[soupir]
I was only gone for a minute.
When I came back, it was like this.
And I bet nobody came forward.
[sighs] People will do anything.
Can you repair it?
No, no, no. Repairing it
would cost more than buying a new one.
Attendez.
[Claire]
How am I supposed to pass my audition?
[Lorenzo] Attendez…
Voilà.
-Ah!
-[brief violin note]
Give this one a try.
[jeu de virtuose]
[morceau mélancolique]
It sounds so incredible.
- Il coûte combien ?
- 3000 francs.
-Three thousand francs.
-[Claire sighs]
I can't afford it.
Well, that's too bad.
Then let's rent it.
[elle soupire]
And who's this?
Uh, Assane. He's a friend.
Your sign says it's 350 francs a day.
Oui. Mais pas pour vous.
- Pourquoi ?
- Oui.
Because… you're in my shop.
It's my decision.
[Lorenzo]
Bonne chance pour votre concours.
Viens, Assane.
On y va !
[door opens]
[Assane] Raciste.
[door closes]
[suspenseful music playing]
- Vous connaissez la région ?
- Non.
Pull out your phone, see where we are.
Figure out where they could've gone.
[Guédira] Alors, attendez…
Y a pas de réseau !
Doit y avoir une carte, ici !
They're passing through Bourneville.
No other road.
-How far?
-I'd say four, five kilometers maximum.
Maybe they stopped there
or someone saw them.
We have to stop there too.
I need to make a call.
Are you kidding me?
No. My wife's still in Étretat and there's
no reception. I need to let her know.
You know how wives are.
If I don't talk to her, she'll think
I'm the one who got kidnapped.
[engine revs]
[musique inquiétante]
[Raoul panting]
[cell phone beeping rapidly]
Allez !
[tonalité d'échec]
Merde !
Regarde ailleurs, toi.
Or I'll have to make you.
[engine stops]
Allez, viens avec moi !
Inside.
Get inside!
[musique inquiétante]
[Claire] Que suggérez-vous ?
We can take you to the station
to file a missing person report.
If we don't hear anything in 24 hours,
we send a general report to all services.
-That's it.
-A general report to all services?
You do realize
we're talking about a kidnapping, right?
OK, vous servez à rien.
- Vous allez où, là ?
- Trouver mon fils !
[musique inquiétante]
[church bell ringing]
If you make a sound, you're dead.
Good choice, kid.
[distant dog barking]
[cloche]
[indistinct chatter]
[les conversations cessent]
Messieurs…
You have a telephone?
Et de la monnaie ?
Sure, for customers.
[inhales and exhales deeply]
[cell phone rings]
-Who is it?
-It's Léonard.
Je suis à Bourneville, en Normandie.
What are you doing there?
I followed our client, like we planned.
But I wanted to tell you that…
there was a small setback.
- Je suis avec son fils.
- Son fils ?
- Oui.
- C'est le père que je veux.
Clean up your mess, and do it properly!
Merde.
[line goes dead]
[musique inquiétante]
[respiration forte]
[Léonard] Messieurs…
[les conversations reprennent]
[Léonard taps trunk]
Keep your mouth shut.
[Raoul panting]
[tires screech]
[musique de suspense]
Monsieur ?
Excuse me. Have you seen a gray car?
With a Black man driving, and a teenager?
Do you remember a gray car? Hey, sir!
Answer me, please.
Even "no" is a response.
-Hello?
-Hey, it's me.
- Toujours malade ?
- Mais non.
-[Belkacem] Are you still sick?
-No, I'm in Normandy.
What the hell's in Normandy?
Get your ass back here. Shit's going down.
-What?
-[Belkacem] We got the wrong Sernine.
- Évidemment, je suis avec lui.
- Quoi ?
He's right in front of me.
-[Belkacem] Sernine?
-Yes, Sernine, yes, Sernine!
Je suis à Bourneville.
-I'm in Bourneville.
-Why the hell are you with him?
Il arrive.
Tout va bien ?
- Tu peux pas parler ?
- Voilà.
[soupir]
[la porte claque]
-Do you need backup?
-[Guédira] Yep.
We need to catch this guy.
Love you too.
Excusez-moi.
A man was here.
He's Black, he's driving a gray car.
With a 14-year-old boy
with brown skin and curly hair.
He's my son. He's been kidnapped.
Si vous savez quelque chose,
dites-le-moi.
For customers.
-[man groans]
-I'm not playing.
[Guédira] That's him!
[tires screech]
[crissement de pneus]
-I'll take it from here. Thanks!
-I'm staying with you!
Trust me. I can help you get him.
Montez.
[musique d'action]
[sonnerie]
Her exam is on Friday
in the 11th district.
-Why would someone break her violin?
-Because they were jealous. For real.
So, if you find the violin,
you're her hero.
Yeah, well, at this point,
I'm more her problem than her hero.
The moron who runs the shop
won't rent her anything
because she's friends with a Black guy.
Sérieux ?
Il aurait fait quoi, Lupin, à ma place ?
Tu le connais mieux que moi.
Moi je pense…
I think
that he would go back to the store,
he'd steal a violin
and give it to Claire.
[suspenseful music playing]
[engine revs loudly]
[tires screech]
Là-bas !
-It's from my wife.
-All right.
[accélération]
[grade crossing alarm rings]
-[train horn blaring]
-[Guédira] No, no, no!
[le klaxon continue]
[musique d'action]
[Guédira sighs]
He shook us off.
[engine revs loudly]
[door creaks]
-[wind whistling]
-[glass tinkling]
[courants d'air]
I'm opening the trunk. Don't do anything.
[cell phone dings]
C'est votre fils.
[Assane taps phone keys]
Ben, non. C'est pas la fille de Lupin
dans Cagliostro.
-It's his son.
-Big fan of Lupin?
- Oui, beaucoup.
- Mon fils aussi.
If he wrote this message,
he'll pick up on the error.
S'il ne la voit pas…
It's a trap then.
[cell phone dings]
[gong de suspense]
[la porte grince]
[wind whistling]
[musique inquiétante]
[glass tinkling]
[Raoul panting softly]
[footsteps approaching]
[Raoul panting]
N'aie pas peur, Raoul, ton père arrive.
[musique angoissante]
I'm gonna say hello.
Et ensuite…
we'll take care of you.
[Raoul groans]
Okay, let's go this way.
Hé !
Vous faites quoi ? Cachez-vous !
Ho !
Hé ! Il vous voit, là !
[vent fort]
[cell phone rings]
Tiens, ton père.
Papa! Papa!
-Hey, shut up!
-Papa!
[Raoul] Papa, here! Papa!
[distant] Help! Papa!
[Assane] If you touch my son,
je te tue.
-[Raoul] Here, in here!
-You want your son?
Viens le chercher.
[musique de suspense]
[la porte grince]
- Il doit y avoir une entrée derrière.
- Possible.
[Assane] Bon.
[Assane] Fine. We're gonna steal
the violin, but then give it back.
- Quand Claire aura eu son concours ?
- Voilà.
Tu viens ?
If I come, who's gonna look out?
[Assane sighs]
Yeah, yeah.
[musique de suspense]
[distant door slams]
-[zip opens]
-[distant clatter]
[coups secs]
[man] What you doin'?
[Assane panting]
[sirène de police au loin]
[string twangs]
[musique inquiétante]
[floorboards creaking]
[distant door opens]
[dog barks]
[distant door slams]
[key rattles in lock]
- [il chuchote]
- [tintement de briquet]
[musique de suspense]
-We should call the police. They can help.
-No.
The police are either incompetent
or corrupt. Or they're both.
-I don't think that's true.
-Well, believe me.
That guy who kidnapped my son
has the police in his pocket.
Quoi ?
[rattling]
Bon.
Que ferait Lupin à notre place ?
It's not a game.
[radio police]
ARRIVÉE ESTIMÉE DANS 1H25
[Claire laughing]
[girl] Hey, is that Assane?
-[Claire] See you later.
-[girl] Okay, bye.
-Why are you here?
-Just waiting for you.
J'ai un truc pour toi.
Tiens.
Ouvre-le.
-Assane, what did you do?
-Just borrowed. Relax, I didn't steal it.
Vas-y, essaye-le.
- Non, je peux pas.
- Vas-y.
Non !
Joue pour moi !
-Just play for me.
-But you can hear me at the audition.
-Just a little.
-No.
J'ai combien de temps ?
Pour ?
- Avant qu'ils arrivent ?
- Qui ?
-Who?
-Your colleagues at the police station.
-Huh?
-The ones you called earlier.
Votre femme.
Ils arrivent quand ?
Euh… Je sais pas.
You're lying, Guédira.
I know your name and I know you're a cop.
I've looked for you for weeks.
-Only I figured it out.
-I know.
-I'd arrest you if--
-If you were armed.
T'es Ganimard, en fait.
[petit rire]
J'ai combien de temps ?
Je sais pas, une heure, ou un peu moins.
Merci.
-[door slams]
-[Guédira] Hey!
Hey, untie me!
I can help!
I told you,
I don't work with cops.
[Guédira sighs]
[indistinct police radio chatter]
ARRIVÉE ESTIMÉE DANS 45 MINUTES
[door creaks]
[courants d'air]
[craquement]
[distant animal cry]
[glass tinkles]
[creaking]
[clanking]
[souffle du vent]
[door rattles loudly]
[Assane gasps]
[musique angoissante]
[glass tinkling]
[floorboards creaking]
[distant howl]
[tintement de verre]
[distant clatter]
Raoul ?
[Assane yells]
[Assane] Raoul.
[courants d'air]
[la musique s'intensifie]
[Léonard crie]
[coup de feu]
[Léonard yells]
[Assane crie]
Tel père, tel fils…
[Assane panting]
[both grunting]
[Assane grunts]
-[Assane yells]
-[Léonard groans]
[Léonard yells] No!
[Assane panting]
Raoul!
[le violon continue]
Raoul !
[effort]
[Assane] Raoul, can you hear me?
Où es-tu ? Réponds-moi !
[le violon continue]
[Léonard coughs]
-[Assane] Raoul!
-[Raoul] Papa!
-Papa!
-[Assane] Can you hear me?
I'm here, Papa! Papa! Papa!
Raoul !
-Raoul, answer me!
-[Raoul] Papa! Papa!
-[Assane] Raoul!
-[Raoul grunts]
In here! Help me!
Papa, is that you? Papa!
Help me!
-Help me, I'm in here!
-[Assane] Where?
[Raoul] Papa!
-[Assane] Can you hear me?
-[Raoul] Papa!
Raoul !
Help!
[musique dramatique]
Papa!
Faut que je sorte de là !
Papa !
Raoul !
LA PROCHAINE FOIS, ESSAYE LA VOITURE
[panting]
Raoul…
Don't fucking move.
Mon fils.
-He's in there.
-[Belkacem] Hands behind your head.
I said hands behind your head!
[sobbing] My son…
Tes mains !
Donne ton bras.
[la musique dramatique continue]
[Assane] Pardon…
Lève-toi.
Get up right now!
Get the fuck up!
Viens avec moi.
I really believed it.
-What?
-[woman] Come on.
Qu'on était aussi forts que Lupin.
My son, he's in there.
Cut the shit, Sernine.
I'm not gonna fall for it this time.
Don't fucking move!
Raoul.
[Assane sobbing loudly]
Raoul!
[la musique continue]
[mysterious music playing]