A NETFLIX ORIGINAL SERIES
[suspenseful music playing]
-Hello.
-Hey.
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
CLEANER
PERENNA LUIS
Okay, everyone, let's move it.
We got a big night.
[Luis] So, this is the Queen's necklace?
Yeah.
Next week, it goes up for auction.
Probably gonna go for 20 million.
Well, shit.
It's okay, I'm sure you can afford it.
In a million years!
[both chuckle]
[camera clicking]
[camera whirring]
THE QUEEN'S NECKLACE
[distant horns blaring]
[indistinct chatter]
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
[coin rattles]
You look like shit, Assane.
You used to be so handsome.
-Can't you afford a razor?
-[Assane] Sure.
-I just got myself a job.
-You got a job?
Mm-hm.
-[woman] Oh, isn't that wonderful?
-Mm-hm.
[woman chuckles]
-Congratulations!
-[Assane] Thank you.
And what is it?
If I had to guess, I'd say
it's really complicated
and it won't last very long.
Same as usual.
It might be nice
if you stopped hiding things.
For us.
For our son.
Can I see Raoul this weekend?
Of course you can see Raoul this weekend.
[distant siren wailing]
You think he's gonna want to see you?
-He's tired of being disappointed.
-I know I'm not the ideal father.
Well… Saturday at eight?
Saturday at eight.
-Things will change, Claire.
-Yeah, well, we'll see.
I'm gonna change.
[Claire] Tell that to your son.
[Assane] I know I'm a bit late
for the alimony, but…
[Claire] Keep your money.
Buy a present for Raoul.
See you Saturday.
Don't be late.
[soft music playing]
[distant horns blaring]
[Claire sighs softly]
[up-tempo music playing]
[men shouting in distance]
[knock at door]
-Who's there?
-It's Perenna.
Get in.
Got the money?
[Assane] There's a problem.
I don't have the cash.
I was wondering
if Vincent would be willing to--
-Oh! Hey!
-Come here.
-What are you doing? What do you want?
-[man] Out of the way, fucker!
[Assane] Hey! Wait, listen to me!
Wait, wait, wait. Vincent!
Listen to me!
-Oh, shit! Wait!
-[Vincent] Where's my money?
[Assane] I don't have it.
I gave it to my kid's mom.
Oh! Oh, please. Give me more time.
Give me more time.
Interesting.
Maybe we should visit your kid's mom.
No!
Fuck! Don't let me fall!
Pull me up and I'll tell you
how to make some cash. A bunch of cash.
More money
than you'll ever be able to spend.
I'm afraid of heights.
You can't keep me hanging like this!
Right, Kevin, get him up.
[Assane groans]
[car tires screeching on TV]
I'm a janitor now.
At the Louvre.
-Sounds like a shitty job.
-[Assane] That depends.
The artwork I clean,
they're worth millions.
And they're within my reach.
-Every night.
-Okay, and how does this get me my money?
You'll get it.
Next Friday,
a necklace will be put up for auction.
The necklace belonged to Marie-Antoinette
and it's worth millions.
Except the sale won't go
as planned because we…
we're gonna steal it.
Okay, Kevin, throw him over.
[Kevin groaning]
-Fuck, seriously?
-You see? You underestimated me.
-[Kevin groans]
-You didn't look at me.
You saw me,
but you didn't really look.
-Just like they don't look.
-Who's "they"?
The people I work for,
everyone who lives on that side of town.
Everyone on top while we're at the bottom.
They don't look.
And thanks to that, we're gonna be rich.
I need someone
who can be quick and decisive.
And someone with muscle.
And you need someone who knows the museum.
And what about me?
Oh, cool.
This is where the auction's held.
We gotta be careful.
There's cameras everywhere.
Only one place doesn't have cameras. Here.
Janitors' locker room. They don't think
there's anything valuable there.
A separate hallway.
A separate entrance. A separate elevator.
They don't want anyone to see us.
And that means they won't see you.
What do you mean, "you"?
You three go in as janitors
and come out millionaires.
And how do we get in?
Using our good looks?
-[Assane] I'll get you in no problem.
-Where's my badge? Shit.
The real question is,
how will you get out? They'll scan you.
Unless you're taking out trash.
Or bringing in cleaning products.
Spray bottles can be filled with anything.
Bleach. Window cleaner.
Or… chloroform.
When the auction starts,
you go to the locker room.
There, Vincent and Kevin,
you'll steal the guards' uniforms.
You'll need 'em later.
And you, Rudy,
you go to the surveillance room.
There's always one guy in there.
He's always sleeping.
So, nothing to worry about.
And then, you deactivate the cameras.
If the cameras are down for
over two minutes, the police are alerted.
Two minutes after that, they'll scramble.
In three minutes, they'll arrive.
Two plus two plus three.
You have seven minutes not to get caught.
-What?
-It's tight.
But more than enough time
to get to the foyer
where they keep the necklace
after it's sold.
Grab the necklace and exit there,
and Rudy will be with the car.
A discreet, fast car
he will acquire for us.
And we're rich.
And here, observe all the pure gold
suspending a river of diamonds.
-Any questions?
While we risk our asses,
what are you doing?
Who, me?
I'm buying the necklace.
[guide] Right, please follow me
for the rest of the tour. Thank you.
And this is where you work?
A big change from home!
Are your bosses cool?
Let's just say they're… presumptuous.
-"Presumptuous," Assane.
-Oh, Papa, seriously?
[dad] "Presumptuous."
P-R-E
S-U-M
P-T-U-O
U-S.
Bravo, my boy.
-[chuckles]
-[thunder rumbling]
[crack of thunder]
[engine spluttering]
[dad] Mrs. Pellegrini?
-Do you need some assistance?
-No.
No, no.
Thank you.
It's me, madam.
I'm Babakar.
Your husband's new chauffeur.
Oh… I'm sorry.
Excuse me. I didn't recognize you.
I'm sorry. I've got a small problem.
Pop the hood for me, please.
All right.
Hey, get in!
Where are you and your dad from?
Senegal, madam. Close to Thiès.
And your mom?
[thunder rumbling]
[hood closes]
Try it now.
[engine starts]
Yeah, it's good!
Well, thank you very much. [chuckles]
-Let me drive you, madam.
-No, no, thank you.
No, I insist.
Well, then, all right.
Do you know
what they call men like your dad?
A gentleman.
Yeah, it's true.
-[Babakar laughs]
-[Mrs. Pellegrini] It's true.
Gentleman.
[suspenseful music playing]
[cameras clicking]
[guard] Thank you.
Ticket.
Good evening.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
-Good evening.
-Hello, sir.
-[woman] Good evening.
-[guard] Have a good night.
-Welcome, Mr. Paul…
-Sernine.
Thank you. Have a good evening.
Thank you, sir.
[auctioneer] Ladies and gentlemen,
dear friends, please take your seats.
The auction is about to commence.
Hey.
CLEANER
Here you go. Good luck.
[auctioneer]
The legendary Queen's necklace.
The fabulous necklace whose very history
is intertwined with the history of France.
A gift from Louis XVI to Marie-Antoinette,
it disappeared during the Revolution
before resurfacing,
two decades later,
in the hands of Napoleon
who gave it to Joséphine de Beauharnais.
Then began an incredible journey
across all of Europe,
from Tsarist Russia
to the Great Palace of Constantinople,
finally ending up
as one of the secret treasures
of the Third Reich.
It was then purchased by our dear friends,
the Pellegrinis,
from whom it was stolen 25 years ago.
[Babakar] After you, sir.
Open it.
Put the car in the garage.
-I don't want it in the rain.
-Of course, sir.
[auctioneer]
It was considered lost forever.
In reality, it had been dismantled
and the seven gemstones were scattered
to the four corners of the world.
But no one took into account
the tenacity of Hubert Pellegrini,
who tracked down every one of the gems.
And today, the reconstructed necklace
has finally returned home, here, in Paris.
Ladies and gentlemen, if you would,
please welcome the daughter of its owner,
the lovely Juliette Pellegrini.
[applause continues]
[Juliette] Good evening.
[pop song in French playing on radio]
[Assane]
Mrs. Pellegrini said I could use the pool.
Are you the son of the guy
who drives my father?
My name's Juliette.
Now you respond.
It's called a conversation.
My name's Assane.
How old are you, Assane?
[Assane] I'm 14.
Next week.
[Juliette chuckles]
Tell me, Assane.
Is it true what they say about Blacks?
-What?
-[Juliette laughs]
What do you mean?
People say they can't swim.
-Well, I can swim.
-[Juliette] Oh, yeah?
Can I see?
If you swim to me, you get a kiss.
It'll be a real kiss.
Not like your mom's.
[applause]
[inaudible speech]
[Juliette] Thank you. Good evening.
When my father reconstructed
this necklace,
he promised
that he'd do something special.
That's why tonight, proceeds from the sale
will help create the Juliette
and Hubert Pellegrini Foundation.
The foundation will support
future cultural and artistic projects…
You have my thanks.
[applause continues]
[auctioneer] Excellent.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now begin the auction
for the Queen's necklace.
We'll start the bidding
at 17 million euros.
[door bangs loudly]
[distant banging]
Central, we're checking the locker room.
[auctioneer] Well, perhaps we can set
a starting bid of 18 million,
as a warm-up, if I may suggest.
Right, who wants to bid 18 million?
Do I have 18 million?
Eighteen million for Herr Kruger.
Danke schön.
I have 19 million here. Thank you.
Twenty million for the lady in front.
Thank you, madam.
Twenty-one million for Herr Kruger.
Wunderbar.
-They're coming!
-[door bangs]
[Rudy] Hi.
[groaning]
[Rudy] Guys… guys, service!
We have 29 million on the phone.
Do I see 30?
[groaning]
Kevin, Kevin!
[grunting]
-Central!
-Now get that guy!
[groaning]
Thirty-two million for Herr Kruger.
Do I see 33?
We're at 32 million euros
for the Queen's necklace.
[guard] Central to the locker room.
Central, everything okay?
Yeah, we're all good. False alarm.
Copy that.
Thirty-two million euros going once…
Thirty-two million euros going twice…
Oh, I have a 33-million-euro bid
from the gentleman over there, perhaps.
[audience gasps, murmurs]
Thirty-three million euros? Um…
Uh, excuse me. Thank you.
PERSONAL WEALTH: 576 MILLION EUROS
Very good.
So, we're at 33 million euros
for this gentleman.
Thank you and welcome to the bidding, sir.
Thirty-three million euros.
How can you say that kind of thing to me?
Do you have any idea
of the situation I'm in?
You've got me by the throat. Fuck!
Why don't you make yourself at home?
You're not paid to read.
Excuse my husband's behavior.
He's concerned about his business.
Yeah.
I understand.
Why don't you take a book for your son?
Yeah. Choose one.
Ah!
Arsène Lupin, Gentleman Burglar.
Excellent choice.
[auctioneer] Do I have 36?
Thirty-six for Herr Kruger. Thank you.
Thirty-seven.
Thirty-seven million.
Thirty-eight.
Thirty-nine million euros.
Do I have 40 million euros?
I don't have 40?
Thirty-nine million going once…
Thirty-nine million euros going twice…
Thirty-nine million…
Forty million for Herr Kruger.
I'm at 40 million
from our first bidder of the night.
If we'd started at this price,
we would've saved some time.
-[laughter]
-But c'est la vie.
[indistinct soccer commentary
on cell phone]
[man] Shit. He's good!
[crowd cheering on cell phone]
[soccer commentator talking excitedly]
[Rudy] Uh, excuse me?
Oh, shit.
[guard grunts]
[Rudy tapping keys furiously] Come on.
Come on.
Come on!
[panting]
Seven minutes.
We're at 40 million euros.
Do I have a bid for 41 million?
Forty-one million for the gentleman.
Cameras… off.
LET ME KNOW WHEN IT'S DONE
-[cell phone dings]
-Forty-one million euros. Do I see 42?
Forty-one million euros…
-Do I have 42 million euros?
-[woman whispering] Do it.
[auctioneer] Anywhere? Um…
Sir, you're already holding
the highest bid.
Yes.
But I think
this is taking a little too long.
[laughter]
Let's save some time.
I bid 60 million euros.
[audience gasping]
Did I hear you say 60 million euros?
Yes, you did.
Sixty million euros.
Sixty million euros? Very well, um…
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the hour of truth.
Sixty million euros.
-Ladies and gentlemen…
-I can't fucking breathe!
Do I have any other bidders
for the Queen's necklace?
No?
So, 60 million euros
for the gentleman going once…
Sixty million euros going twice…
Sixty million euros going thrice…
Sold to the gentleman. Well done!
Thank you.
Are you afraid he'll betray us?
He won't.
We'll do it first.
Thank you.
-[panting]
-[clock ticking]
Five minutes!
[auctioneer] Everything seems to be
in order, so, thank you.
I must admit, Mr. Sernine, I wasn't
expecting someone like you as a buyer.
Like me?
What do you mean?
Well, I mean…
uh, well, so young!
[chuckles]
And here is your necklace.
Well, when your money transfer
is validated, of course.
Of course.
Mr. Pellegrini is very strict
about procedure.
In regards to that, his daughter
would like to meet you, in case you…
Uh… I don't think so.
Can I see it now?
For that price.
Just a little peek.
The necklace is my baby now.
You understand?
Of course.
All right.
-Thank you.
-It's my pleasure.
[beeping]
[Hubert]
I always put the necklace inside the safe.
Can you get into this room? Yes or no?
Yes, but…
And you're well aware my safe is in here.
-No, I'm not.
-So you say.
I saw you lurking in here the other day.
I… I was dusting the bookshelves.
-Madam, you told me to--
-No, leave my wife out of this!
The truth is that Mr. Diop was found
in a precarious situation
which he pretends is an injustice.
To get revenge, he stole the necklace.
I swear on my son's life, I never--
-Who else was here?
-I have no idea!
Okay, calm down, sir.
At the station, we can clear this up.
-All right?
-Yeah, remove this, uh…
This what, huh?
-This what?
-[officer] Whoa. Calm down.
-Stay calm!
-Let go of me!
-Calm down, sir.
-I didn't do it!
-Let's go!
-[Babakar] Help me, Mrs. Pellegrini!
Tell my son!
I'm innocent!
Let me go!
Voilà.
Ah!
Stop!
Okay, I'll humor you if you insist.
[engine running]
-Evening, sir. National police.
-Hello.
Turn off the engine if you're waiting.
Yes, of course.
[engine stops]
-Have a little respect for the planet.
-Yeah, exactly.
-[officer] All right, good night.
-Good night.
[sighs]
-[watch ticking]
-Come on, you guys.
-[groaning]
-Oh my God!
No, let's talk about this…
[groans]
[Assane groaning]
[groaning]
Hey! What are you doing?
You gotta get out!
[Assane groaning loudly]
[Vincent] Let's go!
[Assane] Help us!
-[muffled screams]
-We've been robbed!
Stop, thief!
[alarm blaring]
[indistinct chatter]
[screaming]
[man shouting]
[alarm beeping]
There was a robbery. No one can leave.
Wait, let me check with Central.
Fuck! Central! Two men escaping
through the maintenance staff's entrance!
[Rudy] Shit. Come on, come on!
What the hell is that?
What the fuck are you thinking, Rudy?
[engine starts]
-Is that what you call discreet?
-It's all I could get! Come on!
I'm gonna kill you!
[engine revving loudly]
[sirens wailing]
[tires screech]
[glass shattering]
-[keys jangling]
-[lock opening]
[men shouting in distance]
[guard] I'll get your father.
Thank you.
-P3!
-[man] Opening gate, P3.
[gate buzzes]
[knocks on door] Diop. Visitor.
[knocks on door]  Diop?
Shit.
I need a doctor! Suicide in P3!
[distant thunder rumbling]
[melancholic music playing]
Hello, Assane.
I'm very sorry.
If there's anything I can do…
Yes, madam.
Thank you, madam.
Excuse me, madam.
Go fuck yourself, madam.
[shouting and groaning]
[Vincent grunting]
Rudy, I swear, I'm gonna kill you!
Vincent, I swear, it's not my fault!
I swear!
[grunting]
[Vincent]
It's that stupid, shitty car you took!
[Rudy] Got a little more torque
than I thought.
Let me go!
[Vincent] Kevin, stop it!
-[grunting]
-[Rudy] It's got really shitty brakes!
Nobody touch anything.
I want statements from everyone.
Both the staff and clients.
Mr. Sernine is a victim. You have no idea
how bad those thugs roughed him up!
We fought back, of course.
It's fine, Thibault.
The captain's just doing his job.
It's okay.
Hmm. I've never heard of your company.
What is it? Nanobay? What is it exactly?
Did you use your cell phone today?
-Well, yeah.
-Then you made me some money.
[cell phone rings]
Mm-hm.
-Hello?
-Captain, it's Guédira.
We've taken the suspects into the station.
We'll interrogate them to see if they had
any accomplices in the museum.
-Did you find the necklace?
-Yeah, we got it back.
-It's going to the lab for analysis.
-Good.
Captain, I have a question.
You know the adventures of Arsène Lupin?
What are you talking about, Guédira?
There's this story about a necklace.
It makes me think of Arsène Lupin.
I've read them all.
Get back to the office
and wait for the results.
Okay.
-On it.
-Okay, thank you.
We have the necklace
and the guys who did it.
-Go home. We'll call if we need you.
-Are you sure?
-Yes, it's fine. Go ahead.
-Thank you very much.
-Thibault.
-Mr. Sernine.
-We'll do the necklace another time.
-Yes. Thank you.
[Assane] Goodbye.
[Assane sighs]
Mr. Sernine?
Do you mind?
Want to search me?
[rustling]
[Assane] It's a souvenir.
Am I under arrest?
[captain sighs]
Thank you, Inspector.
[reporter] The alleged perpetrator
of the theft of the Queen's necklace
committed suicide
in a prison in the Parisian area.
The man, a father originally from Senegal,
was the main suspect in the disappearance
of this precious necklace.
With his death
the investigators have no credible lead
to solve the theft
of the priceless artifact
that was purchased several years ago
by the Pellegrini family.
The necklace was allegedly stolen
by a staff member at the main house.
After many interrogations,
they were convinced
that this man was the perpetrator.
What?
You remind me of your mom.
[Assane] Happy birthday.
[sniffles]
[suspenseful music playing]
Arsène Lupin, Gentleman Burglar.
"We are about to tell you
the story of a thief. Not just any thief."
"And the first thing you need to know
about Arsène Lupin
is that no one knows who he really is."
"In fact,
you may have already crossed his path."
"But let's slow down
and start from the beginning."
NO ENTRY
2 WEEKS EARLIER
[Assane sighs]
["I Got The" playing]
[newsreader]
Good morning to all our viewers.
Welcome to the morning news edition.
Today,
we're starting off with a little history.
We've just received exciting news.
The Queen's necklace, the famous heirloom
that once belonged to Marie-Antoinette,
was finally found last week.
This priceless necklace,
which vanished following a theft
nearly 25 years ago,
will be on display at the Louvre
before being put up for auction
by its owners, the Pellegrini family.
This exceptional auction…
♪ I got the blues
But I don't mind… ♪
[Assane]
"Arsène Lupin is a man of many talents."
"He is a master of disguise."
"He can change his identity
in an instant."
♪ I'm on a downer… ♪
-Sorry, I don't have any openings.
-But the agency told me that…
Well, the agency was wrong.
♪ You do your thing just so
And then I feel okay… ♪
You're from Senegal?
-Bakel. Know it?
-No way, my dad's from there!
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
When I was little,
we'd go to this marketplace.
This guy would play music.
-Wait. You know Abdoulaye?
-Yeah, Abdoulaye!
[both laugh]
Okay, everyone, let's move it.
We got a big night.
[Assane]
"You should never trust Arsène Lupin."
"After all,
his name might not even be Lupin."
"In truth, he has many names."
[Vincent] Huh…
Luis Perenna, what a shitty name!
You need money?
Yeah.
[Vincent] I'll give you 1,000.
Interest is 10% a week.
-Ten per week?
-Uh-huh.
Sound good?
Yeah.
So, I'll be really clear
what'll happen if you fuck with me.
-Thank you.
-[Vincent] Don't return without my money.
[Assane] "He uses his extraordinary talent
to commit his various larcenies."
"No obstacle can get
in the way of his plans."
"But his greatest talent,
without a doubt…"
Excuse me. Thank you.
[Assane]
"…is to always be one step ahead."
♪ I was lyin' ♪
♪ Then you sailed along… ♪
Very good.
[Assane]
"Finally, Arsène Lupin is a lone wolf
who from time to time
calls upon his friends
who may have questionable morals,
but infallible loyalty."
[man] Okay, here's the copy.
All right.
You've surpassed yourself, Benjamin.
Well, it's not perfect,
but I did what I could in a week.
-Next time, give me longer.
-There's no need for a next time.
It's time to move on.
It was just important
for me to get this back.
Thank you, my friend.
[Vincent] Okay, let's go!
[Assane] Help us!
We've been robbed!
[Assane whistling a tune]
[beeping]
[guard] Thank you.
-[Assane] They'll scan you.
-Take a look.
[Assane] Unless you're taking out trash
or bringing in cleaning products.
Oh, fuck, come on! This smells horrible!
Are you telling me?
Don't know who comes in here
to change their kids' diapers.
The Louvre!
Go in as janitors…
and come out millionaires.
[suspenseful music playing]
[phone ringing]
[policeman] Hello? Yeah, Lieutenant?
We just got back to the office.
Great, thanks.
Hey, Guédira.
We got the results from the lab.
Apparently, the necklace is a fake.
Let the buyer know.
His name's Paul Sernine.
-How's it spelled?
-Paul. P-A-U-L.
Sernine. Sernine with an S.
Yeah, Lieutenant.
Small-time thugs with prior convictions.
Minor offenses.
Yeah, all three.
I'll send you the statement.
Of course.
Okay. Bye.
-Well, goodbye then.
-Goodbye then.
[doorbell rings]
[Claire] Oh, you're early?
I told you.
I've changed.
-Raoul! Your dad showed up!
-He isn't late?
Isn't that great?
Thanks for the confidence!
So, wanna tell me what you did last night?
-Wasn't nothing much.
-Nothing much?
-It was low-key.
-I'm sure.
-[loud crack]
-Aah! [chuckles]
-Better, yeah?
-Thank you.
[Assane laughs]
Well, how do I look?
Are you messing with me?
Come here, come here!
-How are you doin'?
-[Raoul] You're smothering me.
I'm your dad. I'm supposed to smother you.
[Assane chuckles]
-[front door opens]
-See you soon!
Bye, Mom!
Salut.
[both chuckle]
[tour guide speaking indistinctly]
I hear you spend
all your time on the phone.
That's a shame.
At your age, I loved to read.
You had to.
Cell phones didn't even exist then.
Now, that's just wrong!
-[Raoul chuckles]
-Not sure you deserve my gift.
A gift?
Here.
I think you'll like it.
Your grandfather gave it to me.
I wish you could have known him.
Arsène Lupin isn't just a book.
He's my heritage. My method.
My path.
I am Lupin.